Gustavo Sanchez

Email: gustavosypr@gmail.com | Pasadena, CA
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gustavosanchez626/

GitHub: https://github.com/g626s | **Portfolio:** https://g626s.github.io/

SUMMARY

Dynamic and highly organized Marketing and Analytics professional. Obtained my Bachelor of Science - B.S. in Marketing from California State University, Northridge. Received my certificate of Data Analytics and Visualization from University of California, Berkeley to continue my life-long learning and professional development. Exploring opportunities, in an environment, that offers great challenges to further help companies and clients advance effectively and productively. Insatiable passion for exploring numbers, data, trends and uncovering useful insights to drive efficiency. Having the knowledge, experience and applicable analytical skills for narrowing the distance of data and information to consumers through measuring and optimizing digital experiences. Strengths including analytical problem solving abilities combined with cross-collaboration across diverse groups, makes me a valuable addition to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• MarTech Stack: Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager

• Frontend Stack: HTML, CSS

• Visualization: Tableau, Looker Studio

• Languages: Python, JavaScript, SQL

• Frameworks/Libraries: Pandas, Plotly, Leaflet, Sci-kit Learn, Skforecast

• Databases: BigQuery, PostgreSQL

• Applications/IDE: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, GitHub

PROJECTS

Great Resignation Analysis - https://github.com/g626s/Great_Resignation_Analysis

- The ultimate goal of this analysis is to determine the underlying factors that led to the recent phenomenon being dubbed "The Great Resignation. Our goal for this project is to find, process, and use the data we can find to see what has caused this shift around working conditions and employment.
- Time series forecasting models, particularly on Scikit-learn regression models, were used to perform forecasting on time series. Skforecast was implemented as well as frequency distribution to predict the selected industries of analysis.

Tableau NYC Citi Bike Visualization - https://github.com/g626s/bikesharing

- The overview of this project incorporated a business proposal and pitch for Citi Bike for a particular group of potential investors.
- The goal and methodology of this project was to analyze the Citi Bike data that was collected in New York City in the month of August and launch a bike sharing business in Des Moines. The month of August was chosen specifically to analyze how the business operates in the peak of summer where tourism is the highest.

Human Belly Button Biodiversity Visualization - https://github.com/g626s/Plotly-Belly-Button-Biodiversity
Dynamic and interactive visualization dashboard and charts using Plotly is with a human belly button diversity dataset.

- Interactive dashboard and charts display bacteria that live inside the human body.
- Upon selection of an id number in a pull down list, the id metadata will be displayed in a div element and the top ten bacterial samples will be displayed in a pie chart and bubble chart.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AdSwerve, Inc. | Denver, CO (Remote)

Feb 2023 - Present

Analytics Intern

• Google Analytics and Google Tag Manager implementation for clients operating in diverse industries. Quality Assurance tasks and implementations

- Auditing clients current digital marketing strategies related to the product and supporting functions of Google Marketing Platform's analytical side and service offerings
- Tag management strategies and implementations, setting up tags and tracking on Google Tag Manager and website sources
- Analyze data produced by implementations to produce reports containing insights and recommendations for improving website performance for assigned clients

Lululemon Athletica | Pasadena, CA

June 2021 – Present

Full Time Educator

- Knowledgeable and up to date on company communication, priorities, roll-outs and any additional information required by the Store Manager; educate on guest-facing initiatives to increase quarterly metric sales objectives.
- Assist in inventory management and the visual merchandising team based on each quarter's strategies.
- Implement cross-marketing strategies and inform guests on local and regional community programs including local studios, instructors and events.
- Developed a product education proposal for educators by understanding and bridging the gap between product knowledge and guest experience in alignment to each product campaign.

Carbon Health Technologies | Los Angeles, CA

March 2021 – June 2022

Medical Intake (Productions)

Production Projects: The Morning Show, Pam & Tommy, Riot Games: League of Legends, 2022 Twitch Streamer Bowl

- Supported and coordinated with site and event leads with setting up testing stations as well as incorporating new methods for improved workflow.
- Effectively utilized Carbon Health Provider application in alignment with the project objectives as well cross-team coordination for testing and marketing purposes that increased new client registration by 3% in our Southern California Region.
- Ensured correct patients have been scheduled, complete HPI, and insert correct COVID specimen collection(s) for required results based on the client's role.

LICENSE AND CERTIFICATIONS

freeCodeCamp March 2023

Responsive Web Design

Google Analytics April 2023

Google

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

Nov 2022

COMPSCI 855 - Data Analytics and Visualization Certificate Program, 3.9 GPA

California State University, Northridge

May 2021

David Nazarian College of Business and Economics

Bachelor of Science., Marketing

Relevant Coursework: Strategic Management, Digital Marketing, Marketing Management, Market Research, Marketing Metrics, Consumer Behavior, Operations Management